Guide to the Yale in World War II Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1940-1946, undated; Series III; 1.25 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Correspondence in the first part of the series is arranged alphabetically by recipient. Immediately following is correspondence to various recipients which is filed alphabetically by writer, Miscellaneous correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
  - To Leyburn, James G.
    - A - B (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - C (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - D - E (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - F - H (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - J - K (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - L - N (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - O (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - P (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - R (Box 9, Folder 123)
    - S (Box 9, Folder 124)
    - T (Box 9, Folder 125)
    - U - Z (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - To Lohmann, Carl Albert
    - A - B (Box 9, Folder 127)
    - C (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - D - F (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - G - H (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - K - L (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - M (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - N - R (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - S (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - T - V (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - W, unidentified (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - To Pruden, Russell G
    - Aschmann, Charles G., 1944 October - 1945 December (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - Clark, Samuel J., 1944 October - 1945 August (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - Ginsburg, Harvey, 1943 April - 1945 December (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - Hammond, Lansing V., 1942 September - 1945 Oct, undated (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - Mahoney, John Edward, 1943 February - 1945 April (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - Mathias, Robert John, 1942 December - 1946 June (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Ruff, William (Includes letters to Mrs. N. Burton Paradise and Alexander Witherspoon)
      - 1942 May-1944 December (Box 9, Folder 143-145)
      - 1945 January - 1946 March (Box 10, Folder 146)
  - To Schreiber, Carl Frederick
    - A - Z (Box 10, Folder 147)
  - To Tinker, Chauncey B
    - Ruff, William, 1945 September - December (Box 10, Folder 148)
    - Wetherbee, Ryamond, 1943 April - 1944 April (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - To various recipients
    - A (Box 10, Folder 149)
    - B (Box 10, Folder 150)
    - C (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - Crowe, Walter Quinton, 1944 June 30-1945 January 2 (Box 10, Folder 151)
    - D (Box 10, Folder 152)
    - Day, Julian (Box 10, Folder 153)
    - E - F (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - G (Box 10, Folder 155)
    - H (Box 10, Folder 156)
    - J - L (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - M (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - N - O (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Nichols, George E., III
      - 1942 April - May (Box 10, Folder 160)
      - 1942 June - December (Box 10, Folder 161)
      - 1943 (Box 10, Folder 162)
      - 1944 (Box 10, Folder 163)
      - 1945 (Box 11, Folder 164)
    - P - R (Box 11, Folder 165)
    - S (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - Sizer, Theodore (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - T (Box 11, Folder 168)
    - W - Y (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence
    - Dennis, Lawrence, 1941 May 14 - December 18 (Box 11, Folder 170)
      Correspondence regarding his advertisment in the Yale Daily News recommending non-intervention in the war.
    - Yale Daily News, 1940 May 26 - 1941 November 20, undated (Box 11, Folder 171)
      Correspondence regarding war polls.
    - A - Z, 1943, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 172)
- Additional material, Accession 2004-M-007
  This addition consists of correspondence written to Gordon S. Haight, Yale professor, by his former students serving in the armed forces during World War II.
  - A-B (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - C-E [includes copy of a proclamation of a day of thanksgiving signed by Wilbur L. Cross, governor of Connecticut, 1938] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - F-H (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - K-L (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - M (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - R (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - S (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - W (Box 1, Folder 8)